[SPEAKER_03]: How far off can they hear you?
[SPEAKER_03]: Like I'm talking now?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, let's try it and see how she sounds.
[SPEAKER_01]: What I'd like to do is to just have you begin by saying, talking about when you grew up, what your family did, schooling, and how you broke into baseball, just, you know, as the memories come back to you.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we just, I have your record here, we pick out a few of the high spots as we go along.
[SPEAKER_01]: You just start talking then.
[SPEAKER_03]: Wasn't many high spots in there.
[SPEAKER_03]: I was never with that kind of a club.
[SPEAKER_03]: I think you can hear me at this distance.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, you can put it over here.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, I tell you, is it on now?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yep.
[SPEAKER_03]: Okay, I started in, well, I played baseball all my life as long as I can remember from the time I was a kid.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I went into the Navy in 1917.
[SPEAKER_03]: And when I went in there, I was playing with a semi-pro team over in New Jersey, and I was an outfielder, a pitcher.
[SPEAKER_03]: No, I wasn't a pitcher, I was just an outfielder.
[SPEAKER_03]: And when I got in the Navy, they needed a pitcher, so I volunteered to pitch.
[SPEAKER_03]: And from then on, I was a pitcher.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I come out of the Navy and went in for semi-pro ball over on New Jersey.
[SPEAKER_03]: And in 1924, I signed with the Yankees.
[SPEAKER_01]: Is this date right on the encyclopedia?
[SPEAKER_01]: You were born January 27, 1896?
[SPEAKER_01]: 1896.
[SPEAKER_01]: 83 years old?
[SPEAKER_01]: I'll be 84 this month.
[SPEAKER_01]: And Ridgefield Park, New Jersey?
[SPEAKER_01]: Right.
[SPEAKER_01]: And what about, is that North Jersey?
[SPEAKER_03]: It's, you know where Englewood is, or Hackensack?
[SPEAKER_03]: It's right in that area there.
[SPEAKER_03]: It's just a short way out of New York, about six miles out of New York.
[SPEAKER_01]: What'd your family do?
[SPEAKER_01]: What'd your dad do?
[SPEAKER_03]: My dad was a milkman.
[SPEAKER_03]: He drove a milk wagon.
[SPEAKER_03]: And at one time he owned dairy.
[SPEAKER_03]: But he loved to gamble, and he gambled his dairy away.
[SPEAKER_01]: and finally wound up driving a milk wagon.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did he play any ball himself?
[SPEAKER_03]: He never played.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was born in Ireland.
[SPEAKER_03]: My mother and father both were born in Ireland, and he didn't know baseball from a balloon.
[SPEAKER_01]: When did they come over?
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, they came over when they were real young.
[SPEAKER_03]: They didn't get married until they were over here.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I had nine children.
[SPEAKER_03]: I was the seventh son.
[SPEAKER_01]: What was Alec's?
[SPEAKER_03]: Alec was older than I was.
[SPEAKER_03]: He passed away last February.
[SPEAKER_03]: He lived out in California in Santa Monica.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a catcher, right?
[SPEAKER_03]: He was a catcher with the Giants and went back to the International League and then came back up with Boston.
[SPEAKER_03]: Were your teammates there?
[SPEAKER_03]: In fact, he and I were teammates at Boston for one season there.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, uh, you, uh, how about your first... you played sandlot ball, you say?
[SPEAKER_03]: Sandlot ball.
[SPEAKER_03]: In North Ridgefield, or...?
[SPEAKER_03]: In Patterson, New Jersey.
[SPEAKER_03]: They had a silk mill team over there.
[SPEAKER_03]: The Patterson Silk Sox.
[SPEAKER_03]: It was a good...
[SPEAKER_03]: In those days, they had real good semi-pro clubs.
[SPEAKER_03]: Real top-notch clubs.
[SPEAKER_03]: And, uh, that's where I went from there to the Yankees.
[SPEAKER_03]: I signed with the Yanks in 24.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, uh,
[SPEAKER_01]: What about 19, 19, 20 and all those early 20s?
[SPEAKER_01]: Were you playing ball then?
[SPEAKER_03]: I was playing with these semi-pro clubs around New Jersey.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did you have a job then?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, I worked over in the county clerk's office in New York.
[SPEAKER_03]: I wasn't in any herd assigned because I was making, I had my job, I was making 50,
[SPEAKER_03]: Fifty dollars a game then was good money up around Philadelphia and Connecticut and so forth.
[SPEAKER_03]: I'd sneak off once a week.
[SPEAKER_01]: How many games a year did they play?
[SPEAKER_03]: They played Saturdays, Sundays, and holidays.
[SPEAKER_03]: And you had a regular contract with them.
[SPEAKER_02]: Was that right?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: It was a good outfit.
[SPEAKER_03]: We played teams like you wouldn't know them
[SPEAKER_03]: The Bushwicks and these colored teams, they had some real good colors.
[SPEAKER_01]: Tony was telling me about that this morning.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: They had some real good colored teams.
[SPEAKER_03]: Those days there wasn't many colored ball players in the big leagues, playing big league ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you have some ambition to be in the big leagues?
[SPEAKER_03]: Never gave it a thought about it.
[SPEAKER_03]: Isn't that funny?
[SPEAKER_03]: Never gave it a thought.
[SPEAKER_03]: I just loved to play.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I just naturally drifted into it, that was all.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you go to the games, the big, big games much?
[SPEAKER_03]: I went to them when my brother was signed with the Giants in 20... 21.
[SPEAKER_03]: 20 or 21.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I used to see quite a few games in.
[SPEAKER_03]: Of course, I didn't get to see many because I was working, and then when I wasn't working, I was playing ball.
[SPEAKER_03]: But we saw the World Series of 21, 2, and 3 World Series.
[SPEAKER_03]: Who was the Yankee scout that finally... Paul Critchell.
[SPEAKER_03]: And remember Ed Barrow?
[SPEAKER_03]: He was the general manager in those days.
[SPEAKER_03]: Came over from Boston and... Brought Ruth with him.
[SPEAKER_01]: Brought Ruth with him.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then all the other players too.
[SPEAKER_01]: He brought half the Boston club with him.
[SPEAKER_03]: In fact, that's what made the Yankees.
[SPEAKER_03]: They had Wade Hoyt.
[SPEAKER_03]: When I was with the Yanks, they had Hoyt, Shockey,
[SPEAKER_03]: Pinnock, Joe Bush, gee, what a club they had.
[SPEAKER_03]: They had Ruth, Musial, Garry.
[SPEAKER_03]: Garry wasn't there when I was in, 24.
[SPEAKER_03]: Our room would move down in New Orleans a year or so with the Yankees, and they sent him back to Hartford.
[SPEAKER_03]: But the next year he'd come up, and if you remember, he had that long streak where they never got him out.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, he had a headache or something.
[SPEAKER_03]: He got out, he never got back in again.
[SPEAKER_03]: That was the worst headache he ever had.
[SPEAKER_03]: That was a long-headed idea.
[SPEAKER_03]: Gary gave him that idea.
[SPEAKER_01]: But he was a good friend of mine, Lou.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did they invite you to New York to sign the contract?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yes, he called me over there and asked me what I wanted to sign.
[SPEAKER_03]: And my brother had been in the Leagues, you see.
[SPEAKER_03]: He had played boss since 1914.
[SPEAKER_03]: And he knew the ropes.
[SPEAKER_03]: So I was a pretty independent kid then.
[SPEAKER_03]: I said, well, I'll take this and that.
[SPEAKER_03]: Barrow says, you're mighty independent, aren't you?
[SPEAKER_03]: I said, yes, sir.
[SPEAKER_03]: He said, I like that.
[SPEAKER_03]: I like that.
[SPEAKER_03]: What was Ed Barrow like?
[SPEAKER_03]: He was a nice, he was big and blustery, but he was a fair guy.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was nice.
[SPEAKER_03]: And at that time, Rupert and Houston owned the club.
[SPEAKER_03]: And that's where they had their troubles.
[SPEAKER_03]: They had two factions on the club.
[SPEAKER_03]: And Miller Huggins was the manager.
[SPEAKER_03]: One of the best managers I ever played for, I think.
[SPEAKER_01]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you get much money that first year?
[SPEAKER_03]: I got $5,000 the first year I played, which wasn't bad.
[SPEAKER_01]: And you stayed right with the team?
[SPEAKER_03]: No, I went down to spring training in New Orleans and made the team that year.
[SPEAKER_03]: Then I never played minor league ball.
[SPEAKER_03]: I played 11 years in the majors and when I was finished up there, well, I had to get out because my arm went bad.
[SPEAKER_03]: So I got out.
[SPEAKER_03]: And since then I've been rumbling around doing all kinds of things.
[SPEAKER_01]: That is interesting that you jumped right to that.
[SPEAKER_01]: That Sandlot bothered a lot to prepare.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, as I say, now they don't have those kind of clubs on the Sandlots.
[SPEAKER_01]: George Yulee jumped right from a team in Cleveland from Sandlots to the Indians.
[SPEAKER_03]: I had a letter, it's around here somewhere, from Trish Speaker to join the Cleveland club.
[SPEAKER_03]: before Yuley joined.
[SPEAKER_03]: And the day that I got the letter, Ben Chapman was killed.
[SPEAKER_03]: Remember that?
[SPEAKER_03]: He was hit in the head and was killed.
[SPEAKER_03]: Of course, he called off all appointments and all that stuff.
[SPEAKER_03]: And they were leaving town.
[SPEAKER_03]: They were only in for the series.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I never got in touch with them again.
[SPEAKER_01]: If they'd have been generous to you then, you might have...
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't know, because my idea was to go to New York, because I lived right there.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I had the offer from the Yankees.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I wanted to play with them.
[SPEAKER_03]: In fact, I wanted to play with the Giants where my brother was over there then.
[SPEAKER_03]: But I wanted too much.
[SPEAKER_03]: They couldn't see that.
[SPEAKER_03]: So I didn't go there.
[SPEAKER_03]: Maybe it's just as well because McGraw was managing then.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was a hard center of attack.
[SPEAKER_03]: And my brother said, you wouldn't get along with him.
[SPEAKER_03]: I said, why?
[SPEAKER_03]: He said, you're too hard-headed, the both of you.
[SPEAKER_03]: You wouldn't get along.
[SPEAKER_03]: So I finally joined the Yankees.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I'd like to have stayed with the Yanks because you could have had some kind of record then.
[SPEAKER_03]: That was the only good club I was ever with.
[SPEAKER_03]: In fact, in St. Louis we finished third, I think, in 25 or 27-1.
[SPEAKER_03]: And then in Washington, where I had a terrible year, they finished fourth.
[SPEAKER_03]: And other than that, we were seller clubs all the time.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's too bad.
[SPEAKER_03]: The Browns and the old Red Sox.
[SPEAKER_01]: How many games do you think you might have won that you didn't win?
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_03]: It's hard to tell.
[SPEAKER_03]: You know, they talk about pitchers doing this and that, and they forget about the clubs behind them.
[SPEAKER_03]: Now, a pitcher might look...
[SPEAKER_03]: I remember one year, George Earnshaw, I had a better earned running record than he had, and he won 25 or 26 games.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I lost 18 games.
[SPEAKER_03]: Of course, it was the club you had behind you, so you couldn't tell.
[SPEAKER_03]: And if you said anything, they'd think you were alibis, especially to reporters.
[SPEAKER_01]: A good example is Walter Johnson.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was with the second division club all his career, till right at the end there.
[SPEAKER_03]: It makes all the difference in the world who you're with and who's playing behind you.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you pitch against Walter Johnson?
[SPEAKER_01]: You probably did.
[SPEAKER_03]: No, I don't ever remember pitching against Walter because he went out a year
[SPEAKER_03]: But I went in in 24.
[SPEAKER_03]: He went out in 24, I think.
[SPEAKER_03]: But I pitched against Cobb and Speaker and that bunch.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was that, did you get a little nervous?
[SPEAKER_01]: It didn't sound like you had any nerves like that.
[SPEAKER_03]: You just figure you did or you didn't.
[SPEAKER_03]: It was one thing or the other.
[SPEAKER_03]: You knew they were great ballplayers.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did you have a pitching coach for the Yankees that year?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, he didn't have anything.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you have to pick it up on your own?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, yes.
[SPEAKER_03]: The only thing I learned from them was the fellas on the club.
[SPEAKER_03]: like Joe Bush and Penick and those men.
[SPEAKER_03]: They were mighty nice.
[SPEAKER_03]: I was just a kid going in there green.
[SPEAKER_03]: But they were real nice.
[SPEAKER_03]: And if you wanted to know anything, went up and asked them, they'd tell you.
[SPEAKER_03]: But they weren't running the FDA to tell you.
[SPEAKER_03]: But they helped you if they could.
[SPEAKER_03]: But coaches nowadays, they have all kinds of coaches for hitting, pitching, running bases, and everything.
[SPEAKER_03]: Those days you had a guy on third and one on first,
[SPEAKER_03]: We used to call them ball boys, because that's practically all they were.
[SPEAKER_01]: You often hear about young players going up, and the old-timers make it as difficult as they can for them.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, but I think that was back in the real, before my time even.
[SPEAKER_03]: All the time I was there, I really enjoyed my 11 years up there.
[SPEAKER_03]: I got a lot of friends.
[SPEAKER_03]: I can tell something that they wouldn't print, I guess.
[SPEAKER_02]: You've heard quite a few of that kind.
[SPEAKER_03]: Now, Babe was pretty much to himself.
[SPEAKER_03]: He had a couple of guys on the club.
[SPEAKER_03]: Bob Musil and me were pretty good buddies, and Joe Bush.
[SPEAKER_03]: Hoyt, Hoyt?
[SPEAKER_03]: He and Hoyt didn't get along too well.
[SPEAKER_03]: Hoyt was a pretty high-class boy.
[SPEAKER_03]: I like Wade, I heard from him.
[SPEAKER_03]: A few years back he wrote me, he was broadcasting in Cincinnati for years.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know if he's still there now.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's retired from that place.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, he was coming down with the club and asked me to see if I could find him some reservation somewhere over in St. Pete.
[SPEAKER_03]: So I heard from him and he wrote me a long letter.
[SPEAKER_01]: I spent three hours with him one evening.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's still in good shape, isn't he?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes, from what I've heard, he's failed somewhat.
[SPEAKER_03]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_03]: Did you happen to, by any chance, see Red Ruffey?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: They tell me Red's in bad shape.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, this was back about three or four years ago.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was he in a wheelchair?
[SPEAKER_01]: In a wheelchair, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: His right arm is strapped to his waist here.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's totally useless.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's been flapped and extracted.
[SPEAKER_03]: What, did he have a stroke?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, he had a couple of strokes and a heart attack.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he was a big manly, he was sharp.
[SPEAKER_01]: Where did he live?
[SPEAKER_01]: He lived in a little village called Beachwood outside of Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_03]: Gee, he was a great pitcher.
[SPEAKER_03]: You know, there's an instance of the kind of a ball club you would.
[SPEAKER_03]: Red used to lose, like the rest of us, we were all in the same boat.
[SPEAKER_03]: We'd lose 16, 18 games a year.
[SPEAKER_03]: And Red was right along with us.
[SPEAKER_03]: He went over to the Yankees and, heck, he was a star.
[SPEAKER_03]: Never changed his style of pitching or anything, he just had the ball clumsy.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was a nice guy, I liked Red.
[SPEAKER_03]: When we trained then, we were over in Pensacola.
[SPEAKER_03]: In fact, we trained right here, in Bradenton.
[SPEAKER_03]: Red Sox did?
[SPEAKER_03]: 1930, I think.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's probably before you were born.
[SPEAKER_03]: But we trained here.
[SPEAKER_03]: They had an old hotel down here, the old Dixie Grand.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I remember that just as well.
[SPEAKER_03]: And last year, a couple of years ago maybe, they tore it down.
[SPEAKER_03]: You know this fellow that blows up buildings and they just fall down?
[SPEAKER_03]: That's what they did with this thing here.
[SPEAKER_03]: An old timer.
[SPEAKER_01]: Why did the Yankees send you out to St. Louis?
[SPEAKER_03]: They wanted to get Shaka back.
[SPEAKER_03]: Remember Irving Shaka?
[SPEAKER_03]: They wanted Shaka.
[SPEAKER_03]: And where I got the bad break, they offered a Bushman over with me, I think, and a pitcher by the name of Geon, and they wanted to send Pip Grass.
[SPEAKER_03]: who turned out to be a heck of a pitcher, as you know.
[SPEAKER_03]: And George Sisler insisted, no, me, they wanted me, send me.
[SPEAKER_03]: So I had to go.
[SPEAKER_03]: So I only stayed with the Yanks one season after.
[SPEAKER_03]: When all the trouble of signing with them was shifted off.
[SPEAKER_03]: That was my bad break, really, the only bad break I can say that I got, that I didn't stay.
[SPEAKER_03]: The club that was up there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you get more of a chance pitching with the Browns than you would have with the Yankees?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: I was strictly a relief pitcher with the Yankees.
[SPEAKER_03]: What was Bo Joe Bush like?
[SPEAKER_03]: Joe was a nice guy.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was a big, strong, bullish guy.
[SPEAKER_03]: A great pitcher.
[SPEAKER_03]: But he was tough.
[SPEAKER_03]: He died some time ago.
[SPEAKER_03]: How did you like George Sisler as a manager?
[SPEAKER_03]: George was just one of those guys, he was too nice sometimes.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was just too nice.
[SPEAKER_03]: He wouldn't get on anybody.
[SPEAKER_03]: He wasn't cut out to be a manager, that's all.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was a great ball player, one of the greatest.
[SPEAKER_03]: But he would not, he was afraid of hurting people's feelings.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was softy about it.
[SPEAKER_03]: But, well, Cobb
[SPEAKER_03]: On the other hand, was rough and tough and he was no good as a manager.
[SPEAKER_03]: So what are you going to do?
[SPEAKER_01]: I guess it didn't matter how good you were as a player.
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_03]: I think one of the best managers, and I never played with him or against him, was Al Lopez.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's what they say.
[SPEAKER_03]: Lopez and my...
[SPEAKER_03]: There's three outstanding managers, in my opinion, that I know of.
[SPEAKER_03]: One of them was Lopez.
[SPEAKER_03]: One of them was Bill McKechnie and Miller Huggins.
[SPEAKER_03]: I mean, that started the game in New Orleans.
[SPEAKER_03]: Now, Huggins weighed 110 pounds, stroking wet.
[SPEAKER_03]: And you ought to see him, boss, had those big bullies around him.
[SPEAKER_03]: Except Ruth.
[SPEAKER_03]: Except Ruth?
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, there was the factions I was talking about.
[SPEAKER_03]: See, Ruth had his gang.
[SPEAKER_03]: I was on Houston, I guess, was on his side.
[SPEAKER_03]: And Rupert, there was a bunch that he controlled on the other side.
[SPEAKER_03]: But Ruth did what he pleased.
[SPEAKER_03]: Anyway, what were you going to do with a guy like that?
[SPEAKER_03]: He'd go out there and hit a couple of home runs and...
[SPEAKER_03]: Pack the people in.
[SPEAKER_03]: You couldn't do anything about it.
[SPEAKER_03]: And he was a big...
[SPEAKER_03]: He was just a nice man.
[SPEAKER_01]: I liked him.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who was... Was Baby Dow Jacobson with you there?
[SPEAKER_01]: He was there.
[SPEAKER_03]: Johnny Tobin, Jacobson, and...
[SPEAKER_03]: That's probably the better-known ones that you would know.
[SPEAKER_01]: What about your interns besides Sisler?
[SPEAKER_03]: See, I was trying to think of names.
[SPEAKER_03]: Gerber?
[SPEAKER_03]: Wally Gerber.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, that's right.
[SPEAKER_03]: And old Ken Williams was in the outfield.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was from out on the coast.
[SPEAKER_03]: Wallace somewhere.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a pretty good team.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, in 2025, I can't remember if it was 25 or 27, we finished third.
[SPEAKER_03]: But they had their big year in 22, I think, when they won the pennant.
[SPEAKER_03]: And then they started to go downhill.
[SPEAKER_03]: But after that, we really never had anyone.
[SPEAKER_03]: When Sisler's eyes went bad, that was half the club right there.
[SPEAKER_03]: And Jacobson started to slow down.
[SPEAKER_03]: All those guys were getting old, Jacobson and Tobin.
[SPEAKER_03]: They all had one good year.
[SPEAKER_01]: What about your catchers?
[SPEAKER_03]: Leo Dixon, Kidman and McConnelly, and Red Hargrave.
[SPEAKER_03]: You remember Hargrave was with Cincinnati?
[SPEAKER_03]: There were two of them, weren't there?
[SPEAKER_03]: Red and Petey, I think they called them.
[SPEAKER_03]: I think the one that was with
[SPEAKER_03]: with us was Pinky.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, they did have a good catcher, Hank Severy.
[SPEAKER_03]: Hank was a good hitter.
[SPEAKER_03]: Just like you said, they had some good ballplayers.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes, I think they had a better record over those years there.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, as I said, by the time I went over, they were all on their way.
[SPEAKER_03]: They were getting older.
[SPEAKER_03]: They were on their way down.
[SPEAKER_03]: Since 22, that's when they had the remit.
[SPEAKER_03]: Marty McManus was another infielder.
[SPEAKER_01]: You had a very good record in 25 there, one of your best.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, that was about the best year I had in 25.
[SPEAKER_03]: I think that's the year we finished there, if I'm not mistaken.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you take any delight in beating the Yankees if you did?
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, sure.
[SPEAKER_03]: You know, I used to love to pitch against the Yankees because if you beat the Yankees, you beat the best in the business.
[SPEAKER_03]: So one day we were in Boston and I pitched a game over in Boston.
[SPEAKER_03]: I beat the Red Sox.
[SPEAKER_03]: And you talk about being misquoted.
[SPEAKER_03]: When we got around these reporters, you know, I was sitting around the hotel lobby chewing the fat and I said, I'd rather pitch against the Yankees than anybody.
[SPEAKER_03]: I'd rather beat the Yankees.
[SPEAKER_03]: You know, it's just an offhand remark.
[SPEAKER_03]: And they had a headline over New York, and it was sporting sheep.
[SPEAKER_03]: I'll put it in the locker room.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did they give me the raspberry when I got to New York?
[SPEAKER_03]: And I didn't say anything that was out of context.
[SPEAKER_03]: I just wanted to tell them that naturally I would rather beat the Yankees.
[SPEAKER_03]: But it said guests would rather pitch against the Yankees than anybody.
[SPEAKER_03]: Much as to say they're just soft stuff.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I always pitched good ball against them, but I usually got beaten in tight ball.
[SPEAKER_03]: How'd you pitch to Ruth and Gary?
[SPEAKER_03]: No way to pitch to those fellas.
[SPEAKER_03]: You just mix them up and did the best you could with it.
[SPEAKER_03]: I had better luck with Ruth than I did with Gary, although one of my...
[SPEAKER_03]: I made the Hall of Fame almost coming in the back door because Ruth hit
[SPEAKER_03]: More home runs off me than he did off any pitch in the league.
[SPEAKER_03]: You know, Rube Waldberg used to be with the heck of a pitcher.
[SPEAKER_03]: He hit four off Rube and four off me that game.
[SPEAKER_03]: So I got in, I stayed in the papers for a long time.
[SPEAKER_03]: Even when I was over here in Tampa, we lived in Tampa for quite a while.
[SPEAKER_03]: And the sport writer over there used to talk about him.
[SPEAKER_03]: And Ruth, he was a funny guy, used to call me cousin.
[SPEAKER_03]: Hey, cousin.
[SPEAKER_01]: Which part did you like to pitch in best?
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you have any favorites?
[SPEAKER_03]: Some of them were short.
[SPEAKER_03]: St. Louis, I spent three years in St. Louis.
[SPEAKER_03]: You could throw the ball out into the bleachers and right field in St. Louis.
[SPEAKER_03]: I think Chicago I liked as well as any because it was regular.
[SPEAKER_03]: It was about 3.30 I think down each line.
[SPEAKER_01]: You've got to catch us in action here.
[SPEAKER_03]: It was about 3.30 down East Line.
[SPEAKER_03]: If they hit a ball, they had to hit it pretty good.
[SPEAKER_03]: But in St. Louis, even in the Yankees, except out in the afternoon when they started to go out towards it, in those days anyway, it was a short right field, 2.90, something like that.
[SPEAKER_03]: But I think I liked Chicago as well as anything.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you think that Ruther hit too many home runs in other ballparks?
[SPEAKER_03]: I think so.
[SPEAKER_03]: Because he didn't hit cheap home runs.
[SPEAKER_03]: I know a lot of these other fellas probably wouldn't.
[SPEAKER_03]: But Ruth, when he hit it more, they were hit.
[SPEAKER_03]: So there was fellas hitting home runs.
[SPEAKER_03]: There's fellas hitting home runs now that
[SPEAKER_03]: They just don't have any business for it.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I think that's because of the ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: And all they emphasize is hitting the wrong ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: They're the fellas that make the money.
[SPEAKER_01]: The scientific game changers then abandon the play for a run or two.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, that's what I loved about players like Kong.
[SPEAKER_03]: See, he was a master tactician.
[SPEAKER_03]: He'd walk when he needed the first base.
[SPEAKER_03]: He'd steal second.
[SPEAKER_03]: He'd probably go to third on an infield out and score a sacrifice for us.
[SPEAKER_03]: And in those days, a couple of runs was, they didn't score them like they did now.
[SPEAKER_01]: He could hit them on runs, I guess, but he just didn't try it.
[SPEAKER_03]: He hit one on me one day, I always remember.
[SPEAKER_03]: Something funny, I think, stands out in my mind.
[SPEAKER_03]: It was in St. Louis.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I got him out about three times.
[SPEAKER_03]: And the fourth time,
[SPEAKER_03]: He'd come up and I threw, I used to throw a forkball, you know the one you hold between your fingers?
[SPEAKER_03]: And I threw him a forkball and boy, he hit it.
[SPEAKER_03]: He hit it and he stood on home plate and he said, I knew you'd throw me that sooner or later.
[SPEAKER_03]: So he was right, he hit the thing.
[SPEAKER_03]: But he was one of the greats.
[SPEAKER_03]: He and Ruth, I think, were the greatest fork players I ever saw.
[SPEAKER_03]: They could do.
[SPEAKER_03]: He could do more things than Ruth, but Ruth was a class-bound sub when it comes to subbing.
[SPEAKER_03]: And he was a good outfielder.
[SPEAKER_03]: A good outfielder.
[SPEAKER_03]: They overlooked that because of his hitting.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, he had a great pitching record for it all.
[SPEAKER_03]: And he was a great pitcher.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was just a natural.
[SPEAKER_03]: Gee, it's a shame he went so soon.
[SPEAKER_03]: He and Gary both, and Gary was younger than him.
[SPEAKER_01]: How about Chris Speaker?
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, another great one.
[SPEAKER_03]: He used to play.
[SPEAKER_03]: In those days, they didn't play way back by the fences when they were hitting.
[SPEAKER_03]: He played a short center field.
[SPEAKER_03]: He could go near the ball with anybody.
[SPEAKER_01]: He could really go back at it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, yes.
[SPEAKER_01]: I've heard it said he made a couple of unassisted double plays by catching the low-line driver who was second in the run and coming in and doubling him down.
[SPEAKER_03]: I wouldn't doubt it, because he played a short center field.
[SPEAKER_03]: But as you say, he could go back.
[SPEAKER_03]: And they didn't hit the ball like they do now.
[SPEAKER_03]: These outfielders now, they back up against the fence so much.
[SPEAKER_03]: And they have to, because I don't care what they say about the ball.
[SPEAKER_03]: It's been made lively.
[SPEAKER_03]: There's no question about it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Where was it?
[SPEAKER_01]: We were over at Zinbeck's house in Sanford earlier this week.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know if you remember Zinbeck.
[SPEAKER_01]: I remember.
[SPEAKER_01]: He has a couple of balls cut right through the middle, showing the center.
[SPEAKER_01]: One in 1932, which was getting lively then, and one in the mid-70s.
[SPEAKER_01]: And you can see the different makeup of the ball, which made this 76 or 70 ball so far more lively, you know.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, the center of it.
[SPEAKER_03]: They claim it was the center.
[SPEAKER_03]: They used to have a corks in it, which was lively enough, and then they had some kind of
[SPEAKER_03]: a rubber with some kind of a liquid inside.
[SPEAKER_03]: What kind did he have?
[SPEAKER_00]: He had the one with the big cork, and then the other one was almost solid rubber, with just a little teeny-weeny bit of cork in the center.
[SPEAKER_03]: They've purposely made them lively because, as you said, people want to see that home run, that's what they pay for.
[SPEAKER_01]: It is a thrill.
[SPEAKER_03]: Look at Kingman.
[SPEAKER_01]: He strikes out.
[SPEAKER_03]: He looks terrible at that bat, and at the same time, if you give him anywhere where he can hit it, he'll hit it out of the park.
[SPEAKER_03]: And there's a lot of hitters like that.
[SPEAKER_03]: As long as they hit that long board, and they go for that because that's where the money is.
[SPEAKER_01]: Ralph Conner said they drive Cadillacs.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_01]: How about Lig Park in Cleveland?
[SPEAKER_01]: It's kind of a tough right field there, but they're short ones.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's where I grew up.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh yes, I remember it was a short right field first.
[SPEAKER_03]: They had a big screen up there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, 290 feet and about a 40 foot screen.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, you had to be careful there.
[SPEAKER_03]: It was kind of tough there.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, of course, you had to change your style of pitching if you were pitching in a ballpark like that.
[SPEAKER_03]: And in Boston, they had a short left field.
[SPEAKER_01]: How would you change it?
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, suppose a guy is an inside hitter.
[SPEAKER_03]: You couldn't dare, you wouldn't dare throw an inside ball in Boston.
[SPEAKER_03]: I mean, he isn't an insider, he's an outsider.
[SPEAKER_03]: But still, you've got to throw to his strength, because if you threw it inside, I could pop one over there myself.
[SPEAKER_03]: I remember Walter Johnson hit one up there when I was in Boston, beat some club, hit it up on that screen and right field, and he couldn't hit.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, did you like your years in St. Louis?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yes, I liked St. Louis.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's where I met my wife.
[SPEAKER_03]: I've got to say I liked it.
[SPEAKER_03]: How did you meet her?
[SPEAKER_03]: You know Danny McFady?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: He's my brother-in-law.
[SPEAKER_03]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: He and my wife, my wife and his wife are sisters.
[SPEAKER_03]: In fact, she lives here in Franklin.
[SPEAKER_03]: She moved down here.
[SPEAKER_03]: Because Danny died in 1966, I think.
[SPEAKER_03]: They lived in Maine, so she moved down here.
[SPEAKER_03]: So... Did he introduce you to... No.
[SPEAKER_03]: There was some other player on the St. Louis club that knew her sister and introduced me to her.
[SPEAKER_03]: So we've been married for 52 years.
[SPEAKER_01]: She liked baseball from the starter.
[SPEAKER_03]: She didn't know much about it, but she learned to like it.
[SPEAKER_03]: She's interested in it now.
[SPEAKER_03]: In fact, I'm probably as big a fan now as I ever was, because that thing there will make a fan out of you.
[SPEAKER_03]: Especially when you retire and don't have much to do.
[SPEAKER_03]: I'm very much interested.
[SPEAKER_03]: I grew up for most any kind of sport.
[SPEAKER_01]: Anything with wrestling.
[SPEAKER_01]: Boxing was something that was very popular in the 20s, wasn't it?
[SPEAKER_03]: It was popular, and I took a liking to boxing.
[SPEAKER_03]: I like boxing now, good boxing, but some of these things they put on there, they're not much.
[SPEAKER_03]: I like football, but of course you get saturated with it down here.
[SPEAKER_03]: They give you too much, but I don't think it does them any good.
[SPEAKER_03]: This club over here in
[SPEAKER_03]: How about that?
[SPEAKER_03]: It's come from nowhere.
[SPEAKER_01]: Four years ago, they were losing everything.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's remarkable.
[SPEAKER_03]: But this fellow McKay, when they brought him to California, he said, give him five years.
[SPEAKER_03]: And he lost 26 straight games.
[SPEAKER_03]: Boy, they got never in a hundred years.
[SPEAKER_03]: What do you get for that?
[SPEAKER_03]: That's a good drafting.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, he drafts.
[SPEAKER_03]: Somebody knows he's a great guy for defense.
[SPEAKER_03]: And that's what made that club.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you play any football in high school?
[SPEAKER_03]: I played it till I got a bad knee and then I quit.
[SPEAKER_03]: I still can feel it sometimes.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was it bothering you in baseball?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, it never did.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you ever have sore arm problems?
[SPEAKER_03]: Never had a sore arm, doggone it, until the last little 1930 in Boston.
[SPEAKER_03]: I came up with a sore arm and I never did get over it.
[SPEAKER_03]: In fact, I bluffed my way through for three more years over in Chicago.
[SPEAKER_03]: I didn't have anything.
[SPEAKER_01]: What about the trade to Washington?
[SPEAKER_01]: I'll just as easily forget that.
[SPEAKER_03]: Because I went to Washington and I had a terrible year.
[SPEAKER_03]: Now, why?
[SPEAKER_03]: The only reason I can think of is 27 was I had a good year, 27 with St. Louis.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, with that club it would be considered a good year.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I went to Washington, of course, they expected I was going to do the same thing.
[SPEAKER_03]: Were you traded?
[SPEAKER_03]: I was traded, yes.
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you remember?
[SPEAKER_03]: Gee, I don't remember.
[SPEAKER_01]: Were you excited about it, or unhappy, or didn't you just take it in stride?
[SPEAKER_03]: No, I took it in stride.
[SPEAKER_03]: Luckily, I was traded four or five times, but every time I was traded, it was after the season was over.
[SPEAKER_03]: I was never traded during the season.
[SPEAKER_03]: which is tough up here, because you break up living in Anderson or in whatever city you're in.
[SPEAKER_03]: But I was always traded after the season was over.
[SPEAKER_03]: So I went over to Washington, and the year before I had a pretty good year in St. Louis.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I whooped it up that winter, thought I was pretty good.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I got fat.
[SPEAKER_02]: And when I went over there, boy, they ran me.
[SPEAKER_03]: Bump Hadley, remember him?
[SPEAKER_03]: Bump was over there too, and he was fat.
[SPEAKER_03]: And they rained us in spring training until our tongues were numb.
[SPEAKER_03]: We couldn't.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I use that for an excuse, I don't know if it is or not.
[SPEAKER_03]: But I didn't have a good year at all over there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was Walter Johnson managing then?
[SPEAKER_03]: No, Bucky Harris.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, Harris.
[SPEAKER_03]: And Harris didn't think much of me, so I didn't blame him.
[SPEAKER_03]: So I was traded then to Boston.
[SPEAKER_03]: I was happiest in Boston.
[SPEAKER_03]: I had some good balls.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was Jackie Hayes with you in Washington?
[SPEAKER_01]: Jackie Hayes.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was in Washington.
[SPEAKER_01]: You know, he went blind.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, we interviewed him.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you?
[SPEAKER_01]: Years ago, over in Alabama.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he went blind.
[SPEAKER_03]: Isn't that terrible?
[SPEAKER_03]: It is, but his courage is the greatest.
[SPEAKER_01]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, he was always a live one.
[SPEAKER_01]: Still is?
[SPEAKER_01]: He never let that get him down and has been a real example to blind boys and girls that have this ahead of them.
[SPEAKER_03]: What was it?
[SPEAKER_03]: Glaucoma?
[SPEAKER_01]: He doesn't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: No one knows.
[SPEAKER_01]: Just dizziness developed in 1940 spring training.
[SPEAKER_01]: Isn't that something?
[SPEAKER_01]: I wonder if he was on that team.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was over there.
[SPEAKER_03]: And Fred Marbury, remember him?
[SPEAKER_03]: He was a great relief pitcher.
[SPEAKER_03]: I understand Fred lost an arm or something after he got out.
[SPEAKER_03]: Joe Judge was on first base.
[SPEAKER_03]: Ashley Bluejee.
[SPEAKER_03]: Joe Judge was a good ball player.
[SPEAKER_03]: Muddy Rule.
[SPEAKER_03]: How about shortstop?
[SPEAKER_03]: Young Reeves was shortstop then.
[SPEAKER_03]: Bobby Reeves.
[SPEAKER_01]: What did you have in the outfield?
[SPEAKER_01]: Earl McNeely, was he around?
[SPEAKER_03]: Gosling.
[SPEAKER_01]: Rice, Sam Rice.
[SPEAKER_03]: Rice, Sam Rice.
[SPEAKER_03]: I guess he was.
[SPEAKER_03]: No, he wasn't there.
[SPEAKER_03]: I can't think of him.
[SPEAKER_03]: That was a great ball.
[SPEAKER_03]: They had a good ball, but they finished fourth that year.
[SPEAKER_03]: And if they got any pitching, especially for me, which I didn't do anything.
[SPEAKER_03]: They could have been right up.
[SPEAKER_03]: In fact, in 1924, when I joined the Yankees, we lost the pennant to Washington by about a game and a half or so.
[SPEAKER_03]: That was a dunk on it.
[SPEAKER_03]: I wanted to be in that World Series.
[SPEAKER_03]: We were getting closer and closer.
[SPEAKER_03]: And they beat us out at the last... That's when Walter Johnson was pitching for me.
[SPEAKER_01]: Roger Peckinpah, Marty Rowe.
[SPEAKER_01]: Peckinpah just lived a few blocks away from her family there in Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_03]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_01]: And I saw him a couple of times.
[SPEAKER_03]: You run into quite a few of them, don't you?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, about 75 or so up till now.
[SPEAKER_03]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_01]: We begin to talk to people who've talked to other people, you know, and a lot of fill-ins there, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: There's quite a few of them around this neighborhood.
[SPEAKER_03]: Do you know Henry Ward Johnson?
[SPEAKER_03]: Henry Johnson?
[SPEAKER_03]: In fact, I was now, when we first came down here, about six years, it'll be six years in July, I went over to get my driver's license, plates, I think, at the tag agency, and I gave them a check for the plates.
[SPEAKER_03]: Of course, they had an okay to check, and they sent me over to this fellow sitting at a desk over there, and I gave him the check, and he looked at it, and he says, you're still there with the same address?
[SPEAKER_02]: I said, what's he getting tough on me for?
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't know this yet.
[SPEAKER_03]: I said, yes, I do.
[SPEAKER_03]: He stuck out his hand and he said, Henry Johnson.
[SPEAKER_03]: I didn't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, it's years since I've seen him.
[SPEAKER_01]: Is he far from here?
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't think he's too far from here.
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't know just what section he lives in.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was brought up here.
[SPEAKER_02]: I think he was born in this city.
[SPEAKER_03]: These folks were old-timers.
[SPEAKER_03]: In fact, there was an article not too long ago in one of these sporting columns.
[SPEAKER_03]: This fellow thought that they ought to name Payne Field, not Payne Field, the one down here in Bradenton, name it Henry Johnson Field.
[SPEAKER_03]: That would be bad.
[SPEAKER_03]: You know, Jack Russell is over here in Clearwater.
[SPEAKER_03]: They named it after him over there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Al Lopez?
[SPEAKER_03]: Al Lopez, yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: Russell had quite a career.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was a city commissioner.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was a top-notch amateur golfer.
[SPEAKER_03]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: He played.
[SPEAKER_03]: I think he won the seniors one year.
[SPEAKER_03]: Still plays a lot.
[SPEAKER_01]: Where did you spend your winters in these years in baseball?
[SPEAKER_03]: Around here.
[SPEAKER_03]: Clearwater.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you have a home?
[SPEAKER_03]: No, I didn't then.
[SPEAKER_03]: We stayed in Clearwater for two or three winters and then I bought a home over in Tarpon Springs.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you go back to New Jersey much?
[SPEAKER_03]: No.
[SPEAKER_03]: The last time I was up there was 80, 10 years ago.
[SPEAKER_03]: I had a reunion.
[SPEAKER_03]: My two brothers are gone now.
[SPEAKER_03]: They passed on, but they were alive then.
[SPEAKER_03]: And they said, oh boy, Milt's coming from Florida.
[SPEAKER_03]: Let's get together.
[SPEAKER_03]: A.
[SPEAKER_03]: We had a terrific time out there.
[SPEAKER_03]: And then one of my brothers, Alec, the ball player, moved to California right after that.
[SPEAKER_03]: And that's where he passed on in last year, February.
[SPEAKER_01]: Q.
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you do a lot of hunting or fishing?
[SPEAKER_01]: A.
[SPEAKER_01]: Not anymore.
[SPEAKER_01]: Q.
[SPEAKER_03]: In the off-season, off-days?
[SPEAKER_03]: A. I used to in the off-days, yes.
[SPEAKER_03]: In fact, that's what I
[SPEAKER_03]: That's where I kept in shape, hunting, fishing, played a little golf.
[SPEAKER_03]: I never played a whole lot of golf, but I used to love to hunt and fish.
[SPEAKER_03]: I'd fish.
[SPEAKER_03]: My wife said, Mike, you fish day and night?
[SPEAKER_03]: Anytime they're in there, I'll get them for you.
[SPEAKER_01]: Wanted to come down here, maybe, huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: Part of the reason, I guess.
[SPEAKER_03]: I came down here and we
[SPEAKER_03]: I thought when you come to Florida, you know, it was just a tropical country and that's all there was to it.
[SPEAKER_03]: You didn't have to put on heavy clothes, and I bought a big fishing rod, a sea rod, everything that went with it.
[SPEAKER_03]: I soon learned that it gets pretty cold down here sometimes.
[SPEAKER_01]: We're tent camping on this trip, and we found that out last night up in Tampa.
[SPEAKER_03]: You went into a cold night last night.
[SPEAKER_01]: We sure did.
[SPEAKER_01]: We bundled up.
[SPEAKER_01]: I think my fingers are still not thawed out yet.
[SPEAKER_03]: Where were you?
[SPEAKER_01]: Outside of, near Bush Gardens up in Tampa.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Got down about 30 up there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I lived in Tampa for, oh, 30 years.
[SPEAKER_03]: Had to come home from Tarpon Springs.
[SPEAKER_03]: Went to Tampa, lived there about 30 years, and then, the last job I had over there was a deputy sheriff.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I was with the sheriff's office for about
[SPEAKER_03]: for almost 17 years, and then I retired.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I thought we might like to live in Maine before it's too cold.
[SPEAKER_03]: So we come back here.
[SPEAKER_03]: We wanted to come back to a small town, but Bradenton's not a small town anymore.
[SPEAKER_03]: No, no, no.
[SPEAKER_01]: Bumper-to-bumper traffic down here.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: They're busting at the seams, especially this time of year, don't they?
[SPEAKER_03]: I'd like to be in a small town, but the trouble is you want your cake and eat it, too, because you can't have everything.
[SPEAKER_03]: You wouldn't have all the conveniences and stores and things that the women like.
[SPEAKER_01]: Tell me about after Washington, where you sold or traded.
[SPEAKER_01]: How'd you go up to Boston?
[SPEAKER_03]: I was traded to Boston in one of those multiclared trades when
[SPEAKER_03]: Buddy Meyer, and I went to...
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't remember who went over with me, but it was about four or five players.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I went over there.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I had some of my better years in Boston.
[SPEAKER_03]: How did you feel about that period?
[SPEAKER_02]: I liked it.
[SPEAKER_03]: I liked the idea.
[SPEAKER_03]: Because I had a sister living in Boston.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I liked the town.
[SPEAKER_03]: Not that I didn't like Washington.
[SPEAKER_03]: We didn't take advantage of Washington when we were there, of seeing things and historic things and all over there, you know.
[SPEAKER_03]: But I like Boston.
[SPEAKER_03]: I think some of my best times were when we had...
[SPEAKER_03]: It all depends on who you meet and what kind of behavior you have and so forth.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's challenging.
[SPEAKER_02]: I, of course, would like to have stayed in New York, because I lived there.
[SPEAKER_02]: I lived right across the river.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who was your manager up there in Boston?
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, we had Bill Kerrigan for one.
[SPEAKER_03]: Bill Kerrigan.
[SPEAKER_03]: You remember Bill?
[SPEAKER_02]: The old catcher?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, the old catcher.
[SPEAKER_02]: How was he?
[SPEAKER_02]: He was good, he was good.
[SPEAKER_02]: He used to say, if I had anything but a pitch and a step, he loved his pitch and step, that's all he had.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, it was Red Ruffing, Danny McFady, myself, Jack Russell, and
[SPEAKER_03]: Ed Morris, another great pitcher.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was a good pitcher.
[SPEAKER_02]: But you couldn't do anything.
[SPEAKER_02]: You had to sit in the field.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did Carrigan ever tell you to throw up their heads?
[SPEAKER_03]: No, he never told you, but if you didn't do it, you didn't throw up their heads.
[SPEAKER_03]: I never did anyway.
[SPEAKER_03]: Brush them off, we call them.
[SPEAKER_03]: And that's all you had to do, let them know you were out there.
[SPEAKER_03]: I wouldn't, I wouldn't dare throw up a man's head.
[SPEAKER_02]: I threw out Al Simmons' shins one time, purposely.
[SPEAKER_02]: You know, he had trouble with his feet, and he was a terrific hitter.
[SPEAKER_02]: And the only way he could intimidate him was throwing his feet, because he had bad ankles.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he hollered to the Empire, and the Empire got after me.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I told him, I said, I'm sorry, the ball just got away, I couldn't help it.
[SPEAKER_02]: So we laughed about that.
[SPEAKER_02]: He had that crazy stance.
[SPEAKER_02]: Was that because of his bad feet?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, that was a natural stance.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's not the way you're supposed to stand, is it?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, when he came up there, shoot, they said, he won't do.
[SPEAKER_02]: No, his foot's in the back of the mile, he won't do.
[SPEAKER_02]: Shoot, he hit that ball.
[SPEAKER_02]: He always got it back, I think.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was a great hitter.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was a good ball player besides.
[SPEAKER_02]: You know, they overlooked some of these fellas like Ruth, for instance.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was a fine outfielder, but he hit so good that they just talked about nothing but a setting.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who came after Kerrigan?
[SPEAKER_02]: Bill?
[SPEAKER_02]: He was the coach.
[SPEAKER_02]: Real nice guy, but he wasn't so manly.
[SPEAKER_02]: Of course, managing to me is, if you got the fellas to like you,
[SPEAKER_02]: And he showed a little authority with this bombastic stuff and mocking somebody.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't believe him.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't either.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's good for the cameras.
[SPEAKER_02]: But I don't believe him.
[SPEAKER_01]: It required knowing your players and getting their respect.
[SPEAKER_02]: No, and that's it.
[SPEAKER_02]: The respect is everything because they'll go out and do things for you.
[SPEAKER_02]: And if they don't, they're crazy, because they're probably doing it for themselves.
[SPEAKER_02]: If you get them into everything, you think she knows what you're doing, you won't have any trouble.
[SPEAKER_02]: If you've got the horses, if you don't, you might as well just quit.
[SPEAKER_03]: Because they can't... Bill Kerrigan, in fact, well, he managed the Red Sox way back in 1919, and then got out and then brought them back.
[SPEAKER_03]: He said to me,
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, we're talking about the Boston team in 1930 and 31 there, 29.
[SPEAKER_01]: And some of the players mentioned Russ Garrett, who had a couple of good years, I guess, maybe.
[SPEAKER_03]: He had good years, and he was a real good ball player in AA.
[SPEAKER_03]: I still get in touch with Russ.
[SPEAKER_03]: He called me.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, last year he called me.
[SPEAKER_03]: I expected he might come down.
[SPEAKER_03]: Now, he's from Pensacola.
[SPEAKER_03]: He's lived there all his life, I guess.
[SPEAKER_03]: And he called me last year.
[SPEAKER_03]: I had a card from him, Christmas card, this year.
[SPEAKER_03]: We get a card every year.
[SPEAKER_03]: I'm hoping that he might make a trip down this way one day.
[SPEAKER_03]: Because he was a real good guy.
[SPEAKER_01]: And Earl Webb had his great year we mentioned there.
[SPEAKER_03]: Webb had to set the record for doubles that year.
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't remember which year it was.
[SPEAKER_01]: Tell the story again, if you would, about the grueling watches.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, we got Webby Kepes and grueling watches.
[SPEAKER_03]: They gave one for every home run.
[SPEAKER_03]: So practically everybody in the club had one.
[SPEAKER_03]: Not that they hit the home run, but Webby hit them for them.
[SPEAKER_01]: How about your infield in those days?
[SPEAKER_03]: Let's see, we had Phil Tote on first base.
[SPEAKER_03]: Bill Reagan and Second Base.
[SPEAKER_03]: I think Reeves came over there from Washington.
[SPEAKER_01]: How about Hal Ryan, was he with that team?
[SPEAKER_03]: Hal Ryan, that's right.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was the shortstop.
[SPEAKER_03]: He'd been with Pittsburgh, I guess.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I think... How about Pickering?
[SPEAKER_03]: Was there a Pickering then?
[SPEAKER_03]: Pickering was a catcher, I think.
[SPEAKER_03]: But he wasn't with them, not with Boston.
[SPEAKER_03]: I was trying to think who was on third base.
[SPEAKER_03]: Odie Miller played third.
[SPEAKER_03]: Was he with Boston?
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_03]: I can't say.
[SPEAKER_03]: But I don't remember who was there.
[SPEAKER_01]: How did the town support the team in those days?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, Boston's a great ballpark.
[SPEAKER_01]: Even when the team wasn't doing so well.
[SPEAKER_03]: We would sell it to cellar dwellers all the time, but they'd still come out there.
[SPEAKER_01]: How did that affect the team's morale?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, it doesn't help it any.
[SPEAKER_03]: You know, I used to play in St. Louis on one Saturday, I believe it was on a Saturday, and there was 400 and some people at the ball game.
[SPEAKER_03]: And Washington came into town, and Nick Altra.
[SPEAKER_03]: They didn't have a public announcer in those days.
[SPEAKER_03]: I mean, the system.
[SPEAKER_03]: We had the old megaphone.
[SPEAKER_03]: Nick got the megaphone and he asked all the folks to please move into one station so they could hear him.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was a funny guy.
[SPEAKER_01]: He and Al Trotter went to Washington when I was over there.
[SPEAKER_03]: They used to draw people and sell them.
[SPEAKER_01]: I remember seeing them playing doubleheaders in Cleveland when they were coaching, put on the stunts between the games.
[SPEAKER_01]: They were good comedians, both of them.
[SPEAKER_01]: They knew their baseball too, I guess.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh yeah, Nick was a top-notch pitcher.
[SPEAKER_03]: I never knew too much about Shaq.
[SPEAKER_03]: I think he was a pitcher, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: When they were coaching you, or coaching in the lines there, would they mix in a lot of their humor with the serious stuff?
[SPEAKER_03]: Not too much while they were on the lines.
[SPEAKER_01]: Once in a while.
[SPEAKER_01]: You'd think they're so well known as comedians it'd be hard to ever be able to take them seriously.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, they didn't always coach on mornings either.
[SPEAKER_03]: The funniest thing I saw on the coaching was one day over in Brooklyn, I think that was before I went up there, Casey Stengel was coaching over in Brooklyn.
[SPEAKER_03]: It rained like the day, and they held up the game.
[SPEAKER_03]: Of course, they brought the tarpaulin out and put it on.
[SPEAKER_03]: He went out there with a bucket and a big sponge.
[SPEAKER_03]: Squeezing it in the bucket and throwing it away.
[SPEAKER_03]: And that was really fun.
[SPEAKER_03]: And only he could do it.
[SPEAKER_03]: Another great clown was Rabbit Maranville.
[SPEAKER_03]: One day he'd get in some kind of a...
[SPEAKER_03]: deal there where they had to hold up the game.
[SPEAKER_03]: Or they'd get in an argument, there'd be two fellas getting in an argument or arguing with the umpire and he'd go around sparring with himself and finally hit himself.
[SPEAKER_03]: You had to see it to appreciate it.
[SPEAKER_01]: How'd you get along with umpires?
[SPEAKER_03]: Good.
[SPEAKER_03]: I think I was only throwing out one game that I had.
[SPEAKER_03]: But I got along good.
[SPEAKER_03]: I was smart enough to deal with them.
[SPEAKER_03]: I didn't want to get on the wrong side of them because they could hurt you.
[SPEAKER_03]: They know if they give you a little bit here, a little bit there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you have any favorites?
[SPEAKER_03]: The best one I remember was, I can't think of his name.
[SPEAKER_03]: I had some good umpires, but I was just pointing this one out.
[SPEAKER_03]: Billy Evans.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was one of them.
[SPEAKER_03]: He knew the book.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was smart.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a writer too.
[SPEAKER_03]: He wrote columns all the time.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's what I say.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was smart.
[SPEAKER_03]: He knew what it was all about.
[SPEAKER_03]: If there was any question about the legality of a play or something, he usually had it at his fingertips.
[SPEAKER_01]: They do a pretty good job, you think?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, they do a marvelous job.
[SPEAKER_03]: They're wrong with everybody.
[SPEAKER_03]: No matter what happens, he's got to be wrong with one or the other.
[SPEAKER_03]: And this business nowadays, they exaggerate it, of course.
[SPEAKER_03]: As I say, that camera, that thing there, makes a different ballgame.
[SPEAKER_03]: But look at Earl Weaver.
[SPEAKER_03]: He go out there, and oh boy, he's a great actor.
[SPEAKER_03]: And from what I understand, I don't know, but they claim he's not a bad fellow at all.
[SPEAKER_03]: But you'd think he was the meanest guy in the world when he gets on with those little guys.
[SPEAKER_03]: And Billy Martin loves that camera, too.
[SPEAKER_03]: Billy's out right now, I mean.
[SPEAKER_03]: I hope he stays out, so... Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't...
[SPEAKER_03]: There's no point to...
[SPEAKER_03]: I mean...
[SPEAKER_03]: He's had all the chances in the world, gee.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you ever play a night ball?
[SPEAKER_03]: No, that came in in 1935, I think it came in, because I remember I went over and worked out with the Cincinnati Club, trying to hook on with them.
[SPEAKER_03]: And McPhail was running the club then.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was the boss.
[SPEAKER_03]: And he asked me what I thought of night baseball.
[SPEAKER_03]: I said, they're going to play night baseball.
[SPEAKER_03]: He said, what do you think?
[SPEAKER_03]: I told him I thought it would be a pretty good idea.
[SPEAKER_03]: There would be a lot of people who couldn't get to them in the afternoon.
[SPEAKER_03]: And of course, it turned out to be a great thing.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I had never seen a night ball game except once down in Terre Haute, Indiana when I went down there.
[SPEAKER_03]: When I was with the Red Sox, I came up with a bad arm.
[SPEAKER_03]: They sent me down there to this arm doctor down there, Doc Ferguson.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was an arm specialist.
[SPEAKER_03]: And he couldn't do anything for me.
[SPEAKER_03]: We heard about Bonesetter Reese.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, sure.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was very famous.
[SPEAKER_03]: But this fellow and his brother, I think, finally, one of the two of them, they were arm specialists.
[SPEAKER_03]: But he couldn't do anything for me.
[SPEAKER_03]: My arm was shot.
[SPEAKER_01]: What year was that?
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you remember?
[SPEAKER_03]: That was in 1930.
[SPEAKER_03]: Thirty, no, yeah, thirty.
[SPEAKER_03]: No, thirty-one, thirty-one.
[SPEAKER_03]: Because I was traded over to Chicago in thirty-two.
[SPEAKER_03]: And thirty-two, three, and four, I didn't have it anymore.
[SPEAKER_03]: I was just bluffing my way through more than anything.
[SPEAKER_03]: I was lucky to hang on that long, I guess.
[SPEAKER_03]: How could you bluff, though?
[SPEAKER_01]: I mean, you had to get these guys out.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, you didn't have to have overpowering stuff.
[SPEAKER_03]: You knew how to pitch.
[SPEAKER_03]: Of course, you didn't have too much success at it, but you had enough to get by.
[SPEAKER_03]: What was your best pitch in your better days?
[SPEAKER_03]: I think a fastball.
[SPEAKER_03]: I used to throw a football.
[SPEAKER_03]: One day I'd have a lot of luck with it, and the next day I'd wonder whether who.
[SPEAKER_03]: It wasn't like Suda.
[SPEAKER_03]: Suda can throw that thing every day.
[SPEAKER_03]: But one day I would have luck with it, and another day I wouldn't.
[SPEAKER_03]: When you didn't have it, you just wouldn't use it.
[SPEAKER_03]: You'd go to something else.
[SPEAKER_03]: But I think of fastballs.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I also think if I had the coaching in those days, where they could tell you things, you know, that you wouldn't know yourself or none of the other players in the world, that it would help you.
[SPEAKER_03]: I mean, a good, smart pitcher would watch you and tell you what you might be doing.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you call most of your own games as well?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, we got along.
[SPEAKER_03]: Now, Barry, Charlie Barry, was my catcher over in Boston.
[SPEAKER_03]: And he and I got along good, very good.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, he'd shake me off once in a while, but not too much.
[SPEAKER_01]: Over in St. Louis, I pitched most of my own games.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did the manager interfere much in any of these teams you played with about the pitching?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_03]: They figured if you were up there, you should know what you were doing.
[SPEAKER_03]: Wally Shang was a catcher over there.
[SPEAKER_03]: Remember him?
[SPEAKER_03]: He was a catcher over in New York.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I never shook him off, because he knew he was hitting us.
[SPEAKER_03]: In fact, I didn't shake him off very much.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who was your catcher in Chicago?
[SPEAKER_01]: Muddy Rule was there.
[SPEAKER_03]: Muddy Rule was there.
[SPEAKER_03]: Muddy
[SPEAKER_03]: Money passed on, I guess.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did he ever practice a lot?
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't think so.
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't know whether he did really during the winter, but he couldn't very well because after all, he played all five, six months of the year.
[SPEAKER_03]: He may have had something to do with it, but I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: So you went over to Chicago in 1932.
[SPEAKER_03]: Was that a trade?
[SPEAKER_03]: I was traded to Chicago from Boston.
[SPEAKER_03]: Gee, isn't it terrible?
[SPEAKER_03]: I can't even think of who I was traded for.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's only 50 years ago.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's only 50 years.
[SPEAKER_01]: You shouldn't know.
[SPEAKER_03]: Maybe 60.
[SPEAKER_03]: There's some big left-hand pitcher.
[SPEAKER_03]: I can't think of his name.
[SPEAKER_01]: No, I don't remember the name.
[SPEAKER_01]: Sam Jones was over there.
[SPEAKER_01]: He lived about 25 miles from us.
[SPEAKER_01]: He died in 66.
[SPEAKER_03]: He died prior to fleeing.
[SPEAKER_03]: I never got over to really talk to him.
[SPEAKER_03]: Sam was a great pitcher.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, he was one of that great Yankee staff that I was telling you about.
[SPEAKER_01]: He had Sam Gray, or was it Gray?
[SPEAKER_01]: Gray was there after me.
[SPEAKER_01]: He came later.
[SPEAKER_03]: Was Lou Fonseca there?
[SPEAKER_03]: Fonseca was there.
[SPEAKER_03]: Was Smead Jolly there?
[SPEAKER_03]: Smead Jolly was there.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, you had a lot of fun, didn't you?
[SPEAKER_03]: Smead would play the outfield.
[SPEAKER_03]: I think Smead, they tried to make a catch out of him.
[SPEAKER_03]: But it didn't work.
[SPEAKER_03]: He couldn't catch his pop flies, his power flies.
[SPEAKER_03]: So they put him in the outfield.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was a good hitter.
[SPEAKER_03]: It's a shame.
[SPEAKER_03]: And one day he played the outfield in Boston.
[SPEAKER_03]: They had that embankment I told you about.
[SPEAKER_03]: And they instructed him.
[SPEAKER_03]: They told him, now, Snead, when you're going up after a ball, it's head up there towards the fence.
[SPEAKER_03]: Go up this way.
[SPEAKER_03]: Run up.
[SPEAKER_03]: And then come down.
[SPEAKER_03]: Don't try to run straight up the bank.
[SPEAKER_03]: So somebody hit a ball out there during the game.
[SPEAKER_03]: And Old Sleet played it perfectly.
[SPEAKER_03]: He ran up that way, and the ball fell short of the fence, so I had to come down again.
[SPEAKER_03]: He came down, he fell down.
[SPEAKER_03]: He said, hell, nobody told me about coming down off that bank.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was a funny guy, though.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was his fun and humor and jokes natural?
[SPEAKER_01]: I think it was natural.
[SPEAKER_01]: He just didn't have to make it up.
[SPEAKER_01]: No, he was just a funny guy.
[SPEAKER_01]: I keep the team loose, I guess.
[SPEAKER_03]: A fella like that on the club is invaluable a lot of times.
[SPEAKER_01]: Stop that, boy.
[SPEAKER_01]: How about Fonseca as a matter of fact?
[SPEAKER_03]: I like those.
[SPEAKER_03]: Lou and I got along good.
[SPEAKER_03]: A lot of them didn't like what I liked.
[SPEAKER_03]: How was that on him?
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was a great hitter, you know.
[SPEAKER_03]: He won the title in both leagues.
[SPEAKER_03]: He won the title in the American League and the National League.
[SPEAKER_03]: Great hitter.
[SPEAKER_03]: And he could suck, but I stink.
[SPEAKER_03]: you can't make... you might help a guy up there, but you can't make a hit around him.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was Lou rather easy going, too?
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, he was and he wasn't.
[SPEAKER_03]: As I say, they didn't have the horses, so it's hard to keep you cool in a case like that, I guess.
[SPEAKER_03]: But he and I got along good, even though I wasn't doing much over there.
[SPEAKER_03]: I never did much.
[SPEAKER_01]: You got along pretty well with most of them, though.
[SPEAKER_03]: I didn't have any trouble with any of them.
[SPEAKER_03]: In fact,
[SPEAKER_03]: The years I say I had that bad year in Washington, Paris got down on me.
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't think he liked me very well.
[SPEAKER_03]: I never had a chance to find out.
[SPEAKER_03]: I never talked to him very much.
[SPEAKER_03]: But usually that's the way they are.
[SPEAKER_03]: If you're going good, you're all right.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was Jackie Hayes with you again over here in Chicago?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a good infielder, wasn't he?
[SPEAKER_03]: He was a good infielder.
[SPEAKER_03]: Top-notch infielder.
[SPEAKER_01]: And you had John Watwood?
[SPEAKER_03]: No.
[SPEAKER_03]: He wasn't there.
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't know what I'm saying.
[SPEAKER_01]: I wanted to ask you about Phil Tote.
[SPEAKER_03]: That name always... Phil Tote was a fine fielding first baseman.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was a fancy man and he could field.
[SPEAKER_03]: Great fielder.
[SPEAKER_03]: But his hitting was so-so.
[SPEAKER_03]: But he was a good ball player.
[SPEAKER_03]: That was their trouble over in Boston.
[SPEAKER_03]: They didn't have to hit us.
[SPEAKER_03]: And they had some good ballplayers that come, but they didn't have anything else over there.
[SPEAKER_03]: I mean, they had the pitches.
[SPEAKER_01]: Were you ever a teammate of Lou Blue?
[SPEAKER_03]: First baseman.
[SPEAKER_01]: Blue, gee?
[SPEAKER_01]: Lou Blue.
[SPEAKER_01]: No, the first baseman.
[SPEAKER_03]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: I thought he might have gotten over to Chicago eventually.
[SPEAKER_01]: He traded with Pastor on a few occasions.
[SPEAKER_01]: I always liked that name, Lou Zernatwill Blue.
[SPEAKER_01]: They called him Lou Blue.
[SPEAKER_03]: Lou Lou.
[SPEAKER_01]: Lou Blue like Imolede.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, oh, it was a great life.
[SPEAKER_03]: I really enjoyed myself the time I was up there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Any outstanding thrills?
[SPEAKER_03]: No, whenever anyone asks me that, I tell them just the fact of being up there with these fellas was the thrill I got.
[SPEAKER_03]: It's just being in the big leagues for 11 years.
[SPEAKER_01]: Enjoying it.
[SPEAKER_01]: These years with Chicago, where your arm after your arm had gone, did we find out how your arm went bad?
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you mention it?
[SPEAKER_03]: It just went... Now you see, my big trouble is, here's the story about me.
[SPEAKER_03]: I pitched on the sand lots, and I could beat anybody in the world on them when I was over there in the Jersey prison.
[SPEAKER_03]: These good clubs.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I, in 1921, from 20 on, I had all kinds of offers to play.
[SPEAKER_03]: I wasn't in any hurry because I had a job over in New York, the county clerk's office, a civil service job.
[SPEAKER_03]: I could go out and make
[SPEAKER_02]: money pitching during the week.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I could pitch a game during the week and make, well, $50, sometimes $75, which was good money in those days.
[SPEAKER_03]: So I was in no hurry.
[SPEAKER_03]: I just was in no hurry to sign.
[SPEAKER_03]: But as I was saying, I pitched for until I was 19, 28.
[SPEAKER_03]: I was 28 years old before I went in the league.
[SPEAKER_03]: They thought I was about 23 or 24 years old.
[SPEAKER_02]: Could I interrupt?
[SPEAKER_02]: Would you like a beer or a glass of wine?
[SPEAKER_02]: Or a Coke for one?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, he wants a beer.
[SPEAKER_03]: I could tell the way inside.
[SPEAKER_03]: He's fine.
[SPEAKER_02]: Okay, how ready are you?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, I'll share one with him.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, then I'll have a Coke for you.
[SPEAKER_03]: And, you see, I pitched till I was 28 years old on the sand lines.
[SPEAKER_03]: And that was a lot of pitching in those years, after all.
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't realize you were
[SPEAKER_01]: So older when you went up.
[SPEAKER_03]: If they knew that I was 38 or 39, they would have gotten rid of me before that.
[SPEAKER_03]: They thought I was about four or five years younger.
[SPEAKER_03]: But I had pitched a lot of my baseball before I ever got anything, which was all right with me because I did well.
[SPEAKER_03]: I did all right.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who was your manager after?
[SPEAKER_01]: Did Jimmy Dykes come after Fonseca?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, Jimmy.
[SPEAKER_03]: It was a lock for him.
[SPEAKER_03]: Jimmy was a pretty good manager.
[SPEAKER_03]: But he didn't worry too much about it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Were you a reliever or did you start something?
[SPEAKER_03]: No, I was a regular.
[SPEAKER_03]: In fact, that's the remarkable part of it.
[SPEAKER_03]: I relieved when I went with the Yanks.
[SPEAKER_03]: I was strictly a relief pitcher.
[SPEAKER_03]: Got in about 30 some games that year.
[SPEAKER_03]: And from then on, I was a regular.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I was a regular in every club I was with until the time I quit.
[SPEAKER_03]: Regardless how lousy I was, I was still a regular.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, you won a few games over there with Chicago.
[SPEAKER_03]: Not many.
[SPEAKER_01]: You lost a few, too.
[SPEAKER_03]: We lost a few, too.
[SPEAKER_03]: I think we all did.
[SPEAKER_03]: They had one of the greatest pitches in the business over there at 10 yards.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: I think he won 27 games, even if that's Chicago.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you ever come close to a no-hitter?
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, I was talking the other day.
[SPEAKER_03]: My brother passed on last February, a year ago.
[SPEAKER_03]: No, last February.
[SPEAKER_03]: And they tell the story, of course, after a guy goes and they start reminiscing.
[SPEAKER_03]: And they were talking about him.
[SPEAKER_03]: getting a hit off me in St. Louis when he was with Boston.
[SPEAKER_03]: I was pitching to St. Louis.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I don't remember, they tell the story, that I had a no-hitter going for seven innings.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he got the first hitter.
[SPEAKER_03]: Your own brother broke it up.
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't know how true that was.
[SPEAKER_03]: I know it was a low-hit ballgame and he did get the hit.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, I see.
[SPEAKER_03]: But I don't remember whether it was going towards a no-hitter or not.
[SPEAKER_00]: He doesn't really need it.
[SPEAKER_00]: He doesn't need a glass.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's a real tall beer, isn't it?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: She and I usually split one.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's the extent of my drinking.
[SPEAKER_03]: I drink a beer, we have a beer every day.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was there much drinking in any of those teams?
[SPEAKER_03]: Certain ones, certain ones.
[SPEAKER_01]: There was always a few.
[SPEAKER_03]: There was always a few, but...
[SPEAKER_03]: There wasn't as much as you might read about sometimes.
[SPEAKER_03]: Some of them overdid it.
[SPEAKER_03]: Ed Marshall, I suppose, I could have a picture.
[SPEAKER_03]: Big guy.
[SPEAKER_03]: And he liked his beer.
[SPEAKER_03]: I mean, his liquor.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's the one that got killed?
[SPEAKER_03]: Got killed.
[SPEAKER_02]: Was that out of drinking?
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, he got killed when he was down home in Alabama before he came to spring training.
[SPEAKER_03]: They gave him a party or something.
[SPEAKER_03]: Ed could get mean.
[SPEAKER_03]: I think that might have been what happened to him.
[SPEAKER_03]: But he was a good old boy, but when he got a drink in him, boy, he was...
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a tough son of a gun.
[SPEAKER_01]: Let me ask you a couple of questions here.
[SPEAKER_00]: Whenever he starts to say something to me or wants an answer, I'm surprised at the length of the cigarette.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's so cut out.
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't mean that.
[SPEAKER_03]: You've got to be careful what you say.
[SPEAKER_03]: I have another one.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, you got it.
[SPEAKER_01]: I wanted to ask you how you like baseball.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you go to the games very often?
[SPEAKER_02]: I went to games, especially the time that it meant with pitching.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did it make you nervous when he was pitching?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, he was in a close game.
[SPEAKER_02]: You know what I mean.
[SPEAKER_02]: If he got by, say, the fifth inning and had a lead, I was pretty well satisfied.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did the wives sit together in the various teams he was with?
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you get to travel much with the team, or didn't wives travel?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I came to spring training with him a couple of times, but the other times I stayed home.
[SPEAKER_01]: During the season, though, they couldn't travel with me.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, you could travel, but I took advantage of that with visiting with his parents and with my sister, see, in Boston and New York.
[SPEAKER_02]: Where are you going?
[SPEAKER_03]: Where are you going, sweetie?
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, uh...
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, now you have my life story.
[SPEAKER_01]: A couple more loose ends here.
[SPEAKER_01]: After that 34 season, were you released?
[SPEAKER_03]: Unconditional release.
[SPEAKER_03]: That was my Christmas present.
[SPEAKER_03]: I got it during December.
[SPEAKER_03]: How did they phrase it?
[SPEAKER_03]: That's all.
[SPEAKER_03]: There was a regular little form in those days.
[SPEAKER_03]: They had printing on there.
[SPEAKER_03]: I can't remember exactly, but your contract has been assigned to so-and-so or something else.
[SPEAKER_03]: I've forgotten just what.
[SPEAKER_03]: But they'd written across the front of it here, unconditionally released.
[SPEAKER_03]: So you're through, that's it.
[SPEAKER_01]: No further verbal communication at all?
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you have a hint this might be coming?
[SPEAKER_03]: I had expected it really before that because of the years I was having up there.
[SPEAKER_03]: I wasn't any help to them.
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_03]: But I figured I got in 11 years, so I had no kick.
[SPEAKER_01]: So what, in 35 then, you tried to catch on with the Reds, you said?
[SPEAKER_03]: 35, I tried to catch on with the Reds.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I had this bad arm, as I told you.
[SPEAKER_03]: I didn't do it any good over there.
[SPEAKER_03]: I hurt it worse.
[SPEAKER_03]: Then I went over to St. Petersburg where Bill McKinley was managing the Braves.
[SPEAKER_03]: And Bill was real, he was a nice guy.
[SPEAKER_03]: And he said, where have you been?
[SPEAKER_03]: I've been looking for you.
[SPEAKER_03]: I thought you were coming over first.
[SPEAKER_03]: So I told him, well, I tried out with Cincinnati because Danny McCraden was over there and I thought my wife and his wife being sisters would be together.
[SPEAKER_03]: Bill gave me a uniform, put me out on the mound there to throw the batting practice.
[SPEAKER_03]: And you could tell.
[SPEAKER_03]: And Frankie Frisch was there with him.
[SPEAKER_03]: And they were standing behind the cage when I was pitching, throwing batting practice.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I could see Frisch go like this.
[SPEAKER_01]: Shaking his head.
[SPEAKER_03]: I knew what that meant.
[SPEAKER_03]: So Bill told me, he went in the clubhouse with me and talked to me.
[SPEAKER_03]: He asked me if I could play.
[SPEAKER_03]: And he said, gee, it's a shame.
[SPEAKER_03]: He said, if you can do anything, get it fixed up.
[SPEAKER_03]: He said, you've got a job.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I couldn't.
[SPEAKER_03]: It was gone.
[SPEAKER_03]: That was all there was to it.
[SPEAKER_02]: I tried to get him to take a minor league managerial job.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, I tried to get a managing job, but you had to play at those days.
[SPEAKER_03]: I went up to the meeting in Atlanta.
[SPEAKER_03]: I wanted to manage over, and I had all kinds of minor league offers to pitch.
[SPEAKER_03]: But I couldn't pitch, so what was the sense?
[SPEAKER_03]: So I tried to get a managing job.
[SPEAKER_03]: But you had to pitch in those days.
[SPEAKER_03]: They had managers that were playing, not particularly pitchers, but playing at the same time.
[SPEAKER_03]: So I decided that was it.
[SPEAKER_03]: No, I didn't.
[SPEAKER_03]: I was going to be an umpire.
[SPEAKER_03]: And Ford Frick was the commissioner then.
[SPEAKER_03]: good friend of mine because he, when I first broke in with the Yankees, he was a newspaper man over in New York.
[SPEAKER_03]: And he and I were good friends.
[SPEAKER_03]: And he told me, he said, why don't you go to umpire, you know, he said, I'll keep an eye on you.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, that's all you needed if he kept an eye on you.
[SPEAKER_03]: You only need that encouragement.
[SPEAKER_02]: I couldn't umpire.
[SPEAKER_03]: I tell you, I was the lousiest uptight you ever saw.
[SPEAKER_03]: I saw, I umpired a game between Cincinnati and St. Louis one time in spring training and they liked to kill me.
[SPEAKER_03]: I just couldn't do it.
[SPEAKER_03]: I just couldn't call it.
[SPEAKER_03]: So I decided that wasn't for me.
[SPEAKER_03]: So I said, I guess I better go to work.
[SPEAKER_03]: What did you do?
[SPEAKER_03]: When I first got out, I ran a filling station.
[SPEAKER_03]: I bought a filling station over in Tompkins Springs.
[SPEAKER_03]: I was going to get rich.
[SPEAKER_03]: I lost my shirt on then.
[SPEAKER_03]: I got out of there and I came to Tampa and managed the restaurant.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I quit that and then I went to the sheriff's office and I stayed.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's where I finally wound up.
[SPEAKER_03]: I was with them for about
[SPEAKER_03]: What's 16 years?
[SPEAKER_03]: Deputy Sheriff, police sheriff.
[SPEAKER_03]: I've got a rating on him besides his rating.
[SPEAKER_03]: In Bradenton here?
[SPEAKER_03]: In Hillsboro, up in Tampa.
[SPEAKER_03]: See, we lived in Tampa for 30 years, wasn't it?
[SPEAKER_02]: From 41.
[SPEAKER_03]: 41 to 77.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, over 30 years.
[SPEAKER_01]: You were from St. Louis though, then?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, I was.
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you have any Danny McPhee stories?
[SPEAKER_01]: Danny was a good pitcher.
[SPEAKER_02]: Was he the coach up there?
[SPEAKER_02]: He coached up there for 20 years.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's pretty up there.
[SPEAKER_00]: I love it.
[SPEAKER_03]: I love it in the summertime.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's beautiful in the summer, but boy, it gets too cold for me.
[SPEAKER_03]: I have two 88-year-old cousins living up there and me.
[SPEAKER_03]: You're around.
[SPEAKER_03]: Some of those people you couldn't drag out of me.
[SPEAKER_03]: Now, Danny,
[SPEAKER_03]: Gee, not Florida for him.
[SPEAKER_03]: No, South.
[SPEAKER_03]: You couldn't get him out of that snow country.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think they did give up their hospital for the winter.
[SPEAKER_00]: They moved in.
[SPEAKER_00]: They usually moved in.
[SPEAKER_00]: Last year, they moved in to a hotel in Portland.
[SPEAKER_00]: This year, they moved in someplace else.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because it's the original family homestead from the up in year one or something.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, he wasn't there.
[SPEAKER_03]: Portland, New Brunswick, that was only about 30 miles north of Portland.
[SPEAKER_03]: He had a good job over there, Bowdoin College.
[SPEAKER_01]: played in the years you did it, it was about the train travel.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh.
[SPEAKER_01]: And some of those rides from Boston to St. Louis, or from any place to St. Louis in the heat of the summer.
[SPEAKER_03]: It was a pain in the neck.
[SPEAKER_03]: You didn't have air conditioning, and you'd have your window open, and you know, when you're in your berth, and the old coal burners would throw those cinders back at you.
[SPEAKER_01]: You didn't fly by jet, did you?
[SPEAKER_03]: No, we didn't fly at all.
[SPEAKER_03]: Everything was by train.
[SPEAKER_03]: One trip we made from Detroit to
[SPEAKER_03]: But Cleveland, and vice versa, by boat.
[SPEAKER_03]: We'd go on a boat.
[SPEAKER_03]: That was nice.
[SPEAKER_03]: We liked it.
[SPEAKER_03]: I wonder why they did that.
[SPEAKER_01]: Just as a novelty?
[SPEAKER_01]: I guess so.
[SPEAKER_01]: No trains?
[SPEAKER_03]: It was nice.
[SPEAKER_03]: It was something different.
[SPEAKER_03]: It just trains more.
[SPEAKER_01]: I wasn't crazy about that.
[SPEAKER_01]: On the long rides, you'd play cards and just while away the hours?
[SPEAKER_03]: Did you talk baseball?
[SPEAKER_03]: No, most all of them had their little cliques where they'd play cards.
[SPEAKER_03]: I also want to play bridge, and I want to play pinochle, but practically all of them are playing cars on those trips.
[SPEAKER_03]: In fact, on off days, no, that's mostly what we did.
[SPEAKER_02]: I also started hearing about Charlie Berry died.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was 11.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, he was dead quite a while.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was quite an umpire too, I think.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, he was a 20-year umpire.
[SPEAKER_03]: He came to see us a few years back when we were over in St. Petersburg.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was Moe Berg in any of the teams you were on?
[SPEAKER_03]: No, I don't think I've played with Moe.
[SPEAKER_03]: I wasn't playing against him, but I don't think he was on any of the teams.
[SPEAKER_02]: You didn't play with Ernst Schell either, did you?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yes, Ernst Schell was over in Chicago, I think.
[SPEAKER_02]: That was another nice ballplay.
[SPEAKER_03]: See, they spent a lot of money for that game.
[SPEAKER_03]: Philadelphia, they had Dykes, Ashe, Earnshaw, and Simmons.
[SPEAKER_03]: They brought them all over there.
[SPEAKER_03]: They were going to do big things.
[SPEAKER_03]: But we didn't do anything.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did they move the fence a little bit for Simmons?
[SPEAKER_03]: They moved the fence, and by golly, he got worse.
[SPEAKER_03]: No, they moved his home plate up about, I think, ten feet.
[SPEAKER_03]: And every ball he hit, he ran into the wind coming off that lake, you know, in Chicago.
[SPEAKER_03]: And boy, it hit him a mile, and it broke him.
[SPEAKER_03]: He cuts that place.
[SPEAKER_01]: So you do a lot of golfing during the year?
[SPEAKER_03]: No, I didn't play a whole lot of golf.
[SPEAKER_03]: I played some, but I didn't play a whole lot of it.
[SPEAKER_03]: I think if I had it to do over, I would, because now that's the game.
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you think that was harmful to a hitter?
[SPEAKER_03]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: You just stroke pretty much the same?
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't think so.
[SPEAKER_03]: I'm not an authority because I never played enough of it, but I wouldn't think it would matter.
[SPEAKER_02]: We didn't have the form.
[SPEAKER_03]: We had a lot of fun when we were playing.
[SPEAKER_03]: I'd never get serious about it.
[SPEAKER_03]: Now Jack Russell over here in Clearwater, he got to be one of the best amateur golfers in the state.
[SPEAKER_03]: And he's still probably, at his age, a top-notch golfer.
[SPEAKER_02]: As far as his career, he was still playing.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: So he's had quite a career.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was a city commissioner over there.
[SPEAKER_03]: He ran for legislator or something.
[SPEAKER_03]: He got beat.
[SPEAKER_03]: And he was a senior champion one year.
[SPEAKER_03]: So he's had a good career.
[SPEAKER_01]: Seeing that scrapbook there, the 1920 World Series, I was born in 21, so I missed that.
[SPEAKER_01]: All I heard, for all the years I grew up in Cleveland, all we ever heard was about the 1920 Cleveland game, the Indians, the World Champions, the great year they had, all about the speaker and the Chapman Institute.
[SPEAKER_01]: and Bagby and Kowalewski.
[SPEAKER_01]: As I was a growing boy, I would have given anything to have a pen at a Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_01]: Every time I saw you pitch, you beat us.
[SPEAKER_01]: I got your Goudy card in 1933.
[SPEAKER_01]: I think I tore it up or something.
[SPEAKER_01]: You must get those sent to you.
[SPEAKER_03]: But I don't understand.
[SPEAKER_03]: I get a couple of, usually about a couple of weeks.
[SPEAKER_03]: But they got a little card now with my picture on it.
[SPEAKER_03]: And it evidently has just come out in the last few weeks.
[SPEAKER_03]: I mean, the last few months.
[SPEAKER_03]: Because I bet I've had 10 of them in the last couple of months.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I never saw one before.
[SPEAKER_01]: I bet I know what that is.
[SPEAKER_01]: There's a group organized in New York to reprint pictures of ballplayers in the 20s and 30s on little
[SPEAKER_01]: It was black and white, was it?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, black and white.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's probably what it is.
[SPEAKER_01]: They call it TCMA.
[SPEAKER_01]: They put out a series of about three or four hundred in the 1920s and 30s.
[SPEAKER_01]: I've got all of those, so I'll have to check that over.
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you have any pictures of yourself in action handy that we might take a little look at?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, I've got a... Well, let me show you.